Nichols, Finette Benson Collection Ms B31
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Nichols, Finette Benson Collection
1890-1969
Ms B31
Fairfield Museum and History Center
6.0 Linear feet (15 boxes, 2,000 items, 3 oversize items)
Nichols, Emma S. (Emma Starr), 1874-1947
Nichols, Finette Benson, 1864-1948
Peden, Charles
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
Abraham Benson married Finette Edwards. They had one child, Finette Edwards Benson, who married John Nichols. Their children were: Anna Trowbridge Nichols (d. 14 Feb 1993), Emma Starr Nichols (1874-18 Feb 1947), and Finette Benson Nichols (1864-1948). Finette Benson Nichols was a Republican member of the Connecticut House of Representatives from 1931-1947. Gertrude Johnson of Cornwall Bridge, CT was married to Charles Peden, a film maker for MGM. They moved to the "Benson House", 131 South Benson Rd., which Gertrude inherited in 1949 from her cousin Finette Benson Nichols. Their daughter Marcia (Peden) Miner inherited the house in 1988.
Scope and Contents note
There are 15 boxes and 3 oversize items in this collection. The bulk of the material concerns Finette B. Nichols' legislative papers.
Connecticut Daughters of the American Revolution .; Connecticut State Hospital .; Connecticut. General Assembly..; Fairfield County Republican Women's Association (Fairfield County, Conn.) .; Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939; Child welfare--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Connecticut Tercentenary Celebration (1935); Correspondence.; Education--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Psychiatric hospitals--Connecticut.; Public welfare--Connecticut; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Scrapbooks.; Women in politics--Connecticut.; Women--Connecticut--Fairfield--Societies and clubs.; World War, 1939-1945--Connecticut.
- Papers of Emma Starr Nichols and Finette Nichols, 1920's and 1940's; Box I; 130 items
- Letters and a Scrapbook of Finette Nichols, 1920's and 1940's; Box II; 50 items
- Real Estate Papers of Emma and Finette Nichols, 1920's and 1930's; Box III; 175 items
- Finette Nichols Papers, 1920's and 1940's; Box IV; 150 items
- Finette Nichols Papers and Photographs, 1890's-1940's; Box V; 50 items
- Finette Nichols Political Papers, Fairfield County Republican Women's Association, Child Welfare and Education Papers, 1930's and 1940's; Box VI; 125 items
- Fairfield County Republican Women's Association Bulletins, 1920's and 1930's; Box VII; 100 items
- Finette Nichols Political Papers, 1920's-1940's; Box VIII; 150 items
- Finette Nichols Legislative Material, 1930's-1940's; Box IX; 250 items
- Connecticut Hospital for the Insane Papers, 1910's-1940's; Box X; 200 items
- Scrapbook and Miscellaneous Legislative Bills, 1939; Box XI; 300 items
- Pamphlets and Broadsides, 1920's-1940's; Box XII; 30 items
- Tercentenary Papers, 1935; Box XIII; 30 items
- Charles Peden's manuscripts, Johnson (Kent, CT) Papers and Miscellaneous, 1950's and 1960's; Box XIV; 200 items
- Political, Fairfield Welfare, World War II and Miscellaneous Papers, Box XV; 200 items
- Oversize Item A
  - State Legislature seating plan, n.d.; 2 items
  - Scrapbook, n.d. (Oversize Manuscript Box 2)
- Oversize Item B
  - Photographs of A. B. Jennings and political groups (Oversize Manuscript Box 2)
- Oversize Item C
  - Voting instructions 1935, voting list 1939, broadside DAR Garden Party, news clippings re: A. B. Jennings' interest in Anastasia (Oversize Manuscript Box 2, Oversize Manuscript Drawer)